PRODUCT MANAGER

Executive Profile

Versatile professional with demonstrated ability to increase revenues, boost company visibility, and build solid relationships with business leaders and high level decision makers. Client-centered, results-oriented professional with extensive customer service and distribution ability, enthusiasm, and the desire to succeed. Exhibit solid operations management and organizational capabilities in the planning and execution of multiple projects on an ongoing basis. Proven leadership and supervisory experience, characterized by the ability to achieve Core Qualifications Product Management Sales Analysis & Reporting Project Management Customer Service Management IT/Operations Management 19 years of Industrial Distribution Experience Sales & Sales Support Negotiation Team Building & Leadership Purchasing Warehousing

Professional Experience

Product Manager Jul 2013 to Current

Bank Of America Corporation il/4 Clifton Park, NY

- Portfolio management, negotiation, and rationalization of Band Sawing Products, Machine Tools and Accessories, Precision Measuring Tools, and Hand Tool business units nationwide.
- Enhance relationships with high level executives at key suppliers in the US and Europe.
- Expertly execute and integrate marketing elements with the successful generation of co-op and rebate funding to produce all print, website and social media collateral.
- Successfully negotiate best available discount for resale and payment terms to assist in maximizing profitability and gaining market share.

Sales Support Manager Oct 2011 to Jul 2013

Abbott Laboratories i1/4 Des Moines, IA

- Assisted the Call Center Managers with training and coaching of Customer Service Representatives in all aspects of the call center to better serve our customers and enhance their capabilities.
- Successfully negotiated customer pricing agreements and consignment inventory agreements that maximized profitability.
- Worked with Customer Service Representatives on understanding logistics and freight terms.
- Provided coaching in order to minimize future errors in order to increase efficiency and productivity.
- Performed account level review of price overrides looking for opportunities to increase price and/or margin and make system changes to the
 customer accounts to avoid future override ensuring consistent pricing.
- Assisted customers and corporate accounting as required, resolving customer account issues.
- Coordinated large customer quote requests with the help of Regional Sales Managers, Account Managers, Customer Service, and Sourcing Teams.
- Performed necessary report functions as required by Corporate Executives, Regional Sales Managers, Account Managers, and Customer Service Representatives.

Customer Service Manager May 2011 to Jan 2012

Wegmans Food Markets, Inc. il/4 Bethlehem, PA

- Managed a team of Customer Service Representatives in a call center environment.
- Duties included hiring, training, coaching, discipline, and termination if necessary.
- Assisted the team with an ERP system conversion and maintained a positive working environment during the acquisition of the company and learning new operating processes and procedures.
- Motivated the staff to ensure a high level of productivity to our customers.
- Communicated with internal and external stakeholders to ensure that product or service issues were brought to a prompt and satisfactory resolution with our customers.

IT/Operations Manager May 2000 to May 2011

Midwest Industrial Tools, Inc $\ddot{\imath}$ City , STATE

- Assumed all purchasing duties in the absence of the Purchasing Manger.
- Assumed all warehouse duties in the absence of the Warehouse Manager.
- Managed all projects related to maintenance and improvement of all facilities.
- Performed all adds, moves, and changes to a 75 seat multi-location computer network and telephone system.
- Managed multiple server and PC projects from concept through installation.
- Resolved all server and PC issues on-site, on the phone, and remotely to ensure proper function and un-interruption of service to network and VPN users.
- Maintained all licensing agreements and upgrades to the network and telephone systems.
- Lead the negotiation, purchase and implementation of a companywide telephone system.

Education

Bachelor of Science, Business Management 2000 Bellevue University il/4 City, State GPA: Graduated with Honors GPA: 3.65

3.65 GPA

Graduated with honors

General Studies Business Administration and Management Metropolitan Community College 11/4 City, State

General Studies Business Administration and Management

General Studies University of Nebraska i1/4 City, State

Coursework in Architecture

Skills

Distribution, Customer Service, Call Center, coaching, Prophet21, Prelude, hiring, inventory, logistics, Machine Tools, marketing, negotiation, network, telephone systems, pricing, processes, Purchasing, Sales, VPN, website